CV of Stefan Brus, Software Developer

Code: github.com/stefan-brus

Contact: stefan1brus [at] gmail (dot) com, LinkedIn

Hello World!

I am a software developer with just about 10 years of professional experience. My main focus is on development and maintenance of performance-sensitive backend applications. I consider myself to be language-agnostic, and have both personal and professional experience with a wide range of technologies. Having worked almost exclusively in teams with other developers, I think of myself as a strong team player.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer, Department of Computer Science, Linköping University, September 2009 - June 2010

- Implemented some features & created automated tests for the OpenModelica compiler
- Assisted with miscellaneous projects such as launching and maintaining websites

Software Developer, Ida Infront AB, January 2011 - August 2013

- Main technologies used: Java, SQL databases
- Worked in client-facing teams, developing electronic archives and case management systems
- Additionally, designed some user-facing web forms and data analysis tools

Software Developer, Sociomantic Labs GmbH, later dunnhumby Germany GmbH, September 2013 - November 2015

Team Lead, Sociomantic Labs GmbH, later dunnhumby Germany GmbH, November 2015 - Present

- Main technologies used: The D language, SQL databases, Linux server clusters
- Started off as a backend software developer, and later took over as leader of one of the backend software teams
- Designed, implemented, and maintained real-time performance sensitive network applications
- Heavy focus on ensuring robustness and performance of microservice-based software systems, and single-threaded concurrency models

Education

Computer Engineering, Linköping University, 2006 - 2009

- Focused on software engineering & programming
- Studied maths such as linear algebra, calculus, numerical analysis, statistics
- Learned about software design, operating systems, compilers, basic AI, software security

Skills

Languages

- D (experienced)
- Java (intermediate)
- Haskell (intermediate)
- C/C++ (intermediate)
- Python (basic)

Technologies

- Linux command line
- Git version control
- SQL databases
- NoSQL such as redis, distributed hash tables
- Continuous integration (Jenkins)
- Containers (docker)
- Automation with scripts (shell)